Let's make the title The Divines: Seven Lucky Warriors!
（あおい）
タイトルは
「神仏混淆(こんこう)七福陣」で
いきたいと思います
Animation
Club
Well then, is everyone ready?
（あおい）
ではでは皆さん
準備をお願いします
Let us swear on these Hyotanya donuts...
（あおい）
この ひょうたん屋の
ドーナツにかけまして
（しずか）
我らが
上山(かみのやま)高校 アニメーション同好会は
...that we, the Kaminoyama High Animation Club...
...will do everything in our power to make an original...
（絵麻(えま)）
自主作品制作に努力することを
（美沙(みさ)）
誓いま…
...anime...
...film!
Don-Don-Donuts, let's go nuts!
（一同）
ドーナツ ど～んといこう！
The Divines: Seven
Lucky Warriors
Why don't you just move out of home already?
そんなの さくっと
家出ちゃえばいいじゃん
Zuka-senpai, you make it sound so easy.
ずか先輩 簡単に言いますね
Ema could make it work.
絵麻なら どうにでもなるっしょ
She's really talented at drawing.
絵の才能あるんだし
But what if no studio hires me?
でも受かるかな？　会社
You've got it better than I do! I'm not sure I could even get into a training program!
（絵麻）あっ…
（しずか）そんなこと言ったら―
私なんて
養成所に入れるかどうかだよ
Not to mention how tough the competition is for voice actors.
声優志望なんて
ものすごい倍率だしさ
Sorry, it's too hot! Let me take a break!
ずびばせん…
暑くて ちょいギブです
Mii-senpai, I'll take over!
（みどり）みー先輩 私が
（美沙）うう…
Whoa, it's 36 degrees Celsius today in Tokyo!
へえ～ 東京 今日36℃だって
It's even worse over there?
こっちはまだマシっすか～
Once we move to Tokyo, we better find a room with AC, right, Ema?
絶対 向こう行ったら―
エアコンのある部屋に
住もうね 絵麻
Right.
What? You still haven't decided?
何？　まだもめてんの？
Oi-chan, is it just me or are
donuts not a summer thing?
おいちゃんさあ ドーナツって
夏向きじゃなくなくない？
What do you mean? Donuts make the world go 'round, all year 'round!
えっ？　ドーナツはオールシーズン
オールマイティーの
オール オーケーだよ
They're the best, as far as I'm concerned!
まさに私にとっては完全食！
She moved!
（みどり）動いた！
（あおい）動いてるね～
She really did!
I drew that part!
うん！　今の私が描いたとこ！
やっぱ動くの見ると
ガン上がりますね～！
It's so much more satisfying when I see it move!
でも まだ原画だから
But these are still just the keyframes. We're only halfway done.
作業的には
やっと半分って感じかな
More like a third done. Maybe a fifth—
いや３分の１… ２割…
Why do you have to be such a downer, Ema?
もう 絵麻はなんで
そういうこと言うかな～
Will we really finish in time for the school fair?
え～ だって
学園祭に間に合うかな？
Wanna watch it again?
（あおい）もっかい見ていい？
（一同）見る！
Totally!
Seriously?
（しずか）
マジで？
They'll support me for a year.
（絵麻）
１年だけ仕送りしてくれるって
But I'll have to figure out how to support myself after that.
でも その間に
ちゃんと生活できるようになれって
Did you go on a hunger strike?
（美沙）
ハンストとかやったんですか？
無視とか無言とか家庭内暴力とか
Gave the cold shoulder or roughed them up a bit?
I wrote a letter every day.
手紙 毎日
口だとダメだから
I'm not good with words.
へえ～！　すごい！
That's impressive!
Such perseverance!
粘り腰
I'll be going to Tokyo, too!
私も絶対 東京行きますから
We'll be waiting for you, Mii, Rii.
みーも りーも 待ってるよ
What about you, Oi-chan?
おいちゃんは？
Coming to Tokyo after finishing junior college here?
こっちの短大出たら
東京 来るんだよね？
I... hope so.
ああ… 頑張る
All right, let's run through it once more!
Sequence 01
（美沙）
はい もっかい いきま～す
うう… しゃらくせえ！
10人まとめて引きちぎってやる！
Know your place!
I'll deal with all ten of you at once!
Dream on! You're just a god!
何を～！　神様の分際で！
挑発に乗っちゃダメ！
これはワナよ！
Don't listen to them! It's a trap!
Yeah! It's defnitate—
そうだ ワナに違いなゃ… あっ！
Yup, once more.
（美沙）
はい もっかい～
Sorry...
ごめん
Kaminoyama
High School
School
Culture Fair
Original Animation
Screening
The Divines:
Seven Lucky Warriors
We'll now be screening the
animation club's production,
これより
アニメーション同好会制作
The Divines: Seven Lucky Warriors.
「神仏混淆七福陣」を
上映いたします
We hope you can stay to the end!
どうぞ最後まで
ごゆっくりご覧ください
Produced by
Kaminoyama High School Animation Club
The year is 300,000,000 AD.
（しずか）
時代は西暦３億年
When the Earth lost its soul,
seven godlike divines appeared.
心を忘れた大地に
７人の神様的な人物が現れた
わあ～
心を忘れた大地に
７人の神様的な人物が現れた
Graduation
Kaminoyama
Prefectural
High School
Don't
forget
to lock
the door!
Everyone got a donut?
（あおい）
みんな ドーナツ取った？
Yeah!
（一同）
は～い！
Sometime, in the future, no matter what...
いつか！　絶対！　必ず！
なんとしてでも！
...the five of us...
この５人で
...will make...
アニメーション作品を
...an animated...
作りま…
...film!
Don-Don-Donuts, let's go nuts!
（一同）
ドンドン ドーナツ
ど～んといこう！
That was an email from Anime Wizard-san.
（ラジオ:男）
はい というわけでラジオネーム
アニメ元帥さんからのお便りでした
（女）
アニメ元帥さん いつもメール
ありがとうございま～す
Thanks for all your emails, Anime Wizard-san!
2.5 years later
（男）
まあ確かにね
メールにもあったけど
Just as he wrote,
秋アニメ多すぎて
そりゃまあ何見ていいか
with so much airing this fall,
it's hard to pick what to follow!
迷うわな～
I'm just recording anything and everything for now,
（女）
一応 私なんかも片っ端から
録画しちゃったりしてるんですけど
Ms. Segawa,
Thank you for your hard work.
This is Exodus #4
animation director in material.
I'm looking forward to hearing from you.
Miyamori
but my hard drive's filling up so fast,
I had to delete some shows from summer.
ハードディスクが
すぐにいっぱいになっちゃって
泣く泣く夏アニメ消したりとか
Musashino Animation
（男）
“アニメバブル”とか
言われてるもんね
They say we're in an anime bubble...
つまり いつかはじけちゃう！
It has to burst eventually!
Hey, don't jinx it!
（女）
怖いこと言わないでくださいよ～
（男）
いい時なんて一瞬なんだよ
Good things never last forever!
Miyamori Aoi
Production Assistant
Yeah, yeah. Enough of the doom and gloom.
（女）
は～いはい
そんなネガティブなのは置いといて
Shinotei
（男）
数多くの秋アニメの中からですね
Anyway, out of all the fall anime, we at the AniRadiPokuPoku are most hyped for...
New on menu!
Three kinds of garlic beef bowls
我々「アニラジポクポク」が
１番プッシュしてる作品は
じゃ～ん！　「えくそだすっ！」
Ta-da! Exodus!
Yeah! And since we're so excited for Exodus...
（女）
は～い！　その一押しタイトル
「えくそだすっ！」のですね
（男）
中の人をお呼びしました～！
...we invited some of the voice actors!
Yay!
（女）
イェ～イ！
わあ～！
Good evening!
（声優たち）
こんばんは～！
I'm Nakaharu Mei, playing Akane in Exodus.
（中春(なかはる)）
「えくそだすっ！」あかね役の
中春鳴(めい)です
Thank you for your hard work.
This is Exodus #4
animation director in material.
（伊藤(いとう)）
「えくそだすっ！」あや役の
伊藤鈴鹿(すずか)です
I play Aya in Exodus! My name's Itou Suzuka!
I'm Alpine in Exodus! I'm Kayana Mui!
（茅菜(かやな)）
「えくそだすっ！」あるぴん役の
茅菜夢衣(むい)です
That's Mui with dream and robe kanji!
夢の衣と書いて“夢衣”で～す
（男）
いや すいませんね
Thanks a bunch for making an appearance with us for free!
わざわざノーギャラなのに
お越しいただいちゃって
For free?!
The show's going to be airing soon, so we came to promote it!
（中春）
今日ね この後すぐオンエアなので
宣伝にやってきました
The competition's fierce, so we can't afford to lose!
（伊藤）
は～い ライバル作品多いんで
負けられないんですよ～
（富ヶ谷(とみがや)）
フンッ！
We've gotta destroy—
（茅菜）
うん たたき潰さないとね！
Let's save that touchy topic for another time!
（男）
はいはい 危険な話はね
ここら辺にしといてと
What is Exodus about?
（女）
はい「えくそだすっ！」って
どんなお話なんですか？
It's about the idol group Tracy escaping various situations. The end.
（中春）
はい アイドルユニット
トレイシーが逃げまくるお話で～す
（中春）以上で～す
（男）終わっちゃうの？
That's it? That's one vague summary for sure!
（男）
なんという
まあ ざっくりなあらすじ
Don't worry, we'll fill you in on more of the details later!
（中春）
はい あの内容は
この後じっくりお話しするとして
まずは聴いてください
But for now, listen to this!
It's the opening song we sing on the show as the idol group Tracy!
私たちの演じるアイドルユニット
トレイシーが歌うオープニング曲
It's titled "I'm Sorry, Exodus!"
“あいむそーりーEXODUS(エクソダス)”
soshite sekai ga obiechatte mo
Even if the world frets
shonbori shitecha dame
I won't ever feel down
jikan no mudazukai
Such a waste of time
nigenaide nogarenaide
I won't run away! I won't escape!
todomatte tachidomatte
Let's stop and get this over with
sonna fuu ni tekitou iwanaide
Don't just go around saying stuff like that
mukiatte mukaiatte
Look my way, look at me
hanashiatte aishiatte
Let's talk and share some love
sonna fuu ni tawagoto mou yamete
Don't just make me put up with your nonsense
kurushikattara gaman shinaide
If it's hard on you, don't hold back
nigechae kowarechau sono mae ni
Run away before you get broken
utae odore nigero Tracy
Sing! Dance! Run away, Tracy!
（〝あいむそーりー
ＥＸＯＤＵＳ〞を歌う）
wake ari makuri no aidoru
All idols with troubled pasts
riaru de wa sayonara
The countdown's ticking for real now
koko ni modotte kuru made
I'll be back sooner or later
matteteite ne
Just wait for me
namida kakushite
I'll hide my tears and
exodus
Exodus
Dammit! Not again, Miyamori Aoi!
クソッ！　またお前か
宮森(みやもり)あおい！
ヘヘッ 富ヶ谷さん お先です！
Later, Tomigaya-san.
Exodus Into Tomorrow!
I'm Miyamori Aoi from Musashino Animation!
武蔵野(むさしの)アニメーションの
宮森あおいです
I'm here to pick up the animation director ups for Exodus episode 4!
「えくそだすっ！」４話の
作監上がりを頂きに参りました
Coming...
（瀬川(せがわ)）
は～い
Segawa Misato
Animation Director
Total
Episode
Director
Animation
Tween
Check
Cell Check
Screenplay
Color Setting
Sorry, I don't have much for you tonight.
ちょっと今日 少ないんだけど
Not a problem! Thank you very much!
いえいえ ありがとうございます
That's the last AD in package.
それで これで作監入れ全部です
It's only two days until the final AD up, huh?
あと２日で作監アップだったよね？
The first episode is airing today, right?
今夜 もう１話
始まっちゃうんだもんね
Yeah, it is! Finally!
始まっちゃいます
いよいよです
Oh, so you're actually looking forward to it.
そっか 宮森さんは楽しみなんだ
（あおい）えっ？
（瀬川）私は１話の放映前が―
I always get so nervous before the first episode airs.
一番緊張する
It means I have another 13-episode, 1-cour show to deal with.
待ったなしの１(ワン)クール13本が
始まっちゃうよって
But thanks to you, the quality's through the roof!
瀬川さんに入っていただいて
すごいクオリティーになってますよ
The director's really happy with it!
監督も大喜びですもん
ホント？　だといいな～
Really? I hope you're right.
My shoulders are killing me!
もうね さすがに肩凝っちゃって
Yeah, must be tough.
やっぱり 大変ですよね？
うん？　ああ まあね
Oh well, we're on the home stretch!
We can do this!
あとちょっとだし 頑張りますよ！
Yeah! Thank you very much!
はい よろしくお願いします！
I'm back!
（あおい）
戻りました～！
Honda Yutaka
Production Manager
Fight's gonna be tops this season, I'd say.
（本田(ほんだ)）
今期はやっぱり
「ファイト」かな～
Isn't G-Colle getting all the attention?
Ochiai Tatsuya
Production Assistant
（落合(おちあい)）
注目度だと
「Ｇコレ」じゃないですか？
C'mon, we should at least be more confident in our baby, Exodus.
Takanashi Tarou
Production Assistant
（太郎(たろう)）
いや そこはうちの
「えくそだすっ！」っと
ズバっと言い切りましょ～！
Shimoyanagi Yuuichirou
3D Director
Oh, so you started at that studio?
（下柳(しもやなぎ)）
へえ あのスタジオ
出身だったんですね
The restrooms there are an absolute nightmare!
Doumoto Chiemi
Tween Checker
（堂本(どうもと)）
そうそう
あそこ もうトイレが最悪で
I heard that Kisa-san lost 20 kilograms just by cycling!
Iguchi Yumi
Supervising Animation Director Assistant
（井口(いぐち)）
木佐(きさ)さん 自転車で
20キロも痩せたんですって
And then she got injured and hospitalized, and put 23 kilos right back on!
Ogasawara Rinko
Character Design
Supervising Animation Director
Ogasawara Rinko
Character Design
Supervising Animation Director
でもケガして入院して
23キロ 太ったらしいですよ
I'm so nervous... We're going on air...
Uchida Akane
Keyframe Animator
（内田(うちだ)）
なんか緊張するね　オンエアって
Yeah... I'm really not confident about my drawings.
Yasuhara Ema
Keyframe Animator
そうですね
私の絵で
いいのかなって感じです
By the way, where's NabeP?
Sagura Yoshiki
Filming Director
（佐倉(さくら)）
あれ？　そういえばナベＰは？
Mahjong. Nothing new there.
Arakawa Nao
Color Setting / Check
（新川(しんかわ)）
“天牌(てんぱい)”でしょ　いつものこと
Can't believe he's pulling that when episode 1's gonna air.
Yano Erika
Production Assistant
（矢野(やの)）
１話の放映なのに ありえない
That's how NabeP rolls.
（新川）
ナベＰだから
Kinoshita Shinichi
Director
Director, people are already talking about it!
（円(まどか)）
監督 もう実況 始まってますよ
Madoka Hironori
Episode Director
Give that stuff a rest!
（木下(きのした)）
いちいち言わなくていい！
Madoka, get off the net for a change!
Yamada Masashi
Episode Director
（山田(やまだ)）
円 お前ネット見すぎ
Ah, Miyamori-san!
There's curry for you too!
Marukawa Masato
President
（丸川(まるかわ)）
おっ 宮森さん
カレーあるよ カレー
あっ はい！
Thanks!
Meowmori, got a seat for you!
みゃーもり こっちこっち
20 seconds to go!
Wanna tweet something with the hashtag?
あと20秒です
ハッシュタグ付けて
ツイートでもしますか？
ネットはやらん！
I'll stay off the net, thanks.
Would you stop fidgeting?
貧乏ゆすり やめてもらえます？
ごめん
Sorry.
Ten seconds to go!
（円）
あと10秒！
Seven! Six! Five!
（太郎）７･６･５…
（矢野）太郎 静かに！
Tarou, zip it!
On sale from October 25th!
A Certain
Temple's Mummy
A
（テレビＣＭ）
10月25日オンセール！
（歓声）
（本田）始まりましたね～
It's started!
（木下）
分かってるよ！
Well, duh!
Wh-What do we do now?!
（あるぴん）
どっ どっ どっ… どうしよう？
I don't know...
（あかね）どうって？
（あや）すぐに警備員も来る
The guards will be here soon.
Wait! My grandpa always told me to stay calm in dangerous situations!
（あかね）
待って こういう危険な時ほど
落ち着けって
おじじが言ってた
Watanabe Jun
Line Producer
What a pragmatist you are!
（あや）
さすが
現実主義者のカッパ
Tune in next week too! Exodus!
No Makeup is Real Life!
Next Time
（あかね）
来週も明日に向かって
（あや･あるぴん･あかね）
「えくそだすっ！」
It's real nicely made.
Well done, Kinoshita-kun!
丁寧に作ってあって
いい出来じゃないの 木下君
（木下）
あっ ありがとうございます
頑張ります
Thank you so much!
I'm doing my best.
キーワードランキング２位
きました！
We're trending right now! Yeah, second highest!
（あおい）お～！
（木下）だからいいって
Who cares about that?
そういうの！
Wow, people have written about it already?
早いな～ もう感想か
そこそこ評判いいですよ
The first reviews are okay!
Just okay?
（木下）そこそこ…
（太郎）よかったっすね～
Isn't it great? Maybe this is the start of a comeback!
みそぎ済んだんじゃないっすか？
A comeback...
みそぎ…
Anyone up for seconds?
ああ みんな お代わりあるからね
どんどん食べて
Eat up!
（太郎）
はいはい！　いただきま～す！
I'll have some!
俺も食べよっかな
I guess I'll have some too...
But episode 2 is airing next week already?
（山田）
しかし来週は２話か 早(はえ)えよな～
That's so soon...
That means 3 is the week after!
（円）…てことは その次３話
（太郎）あっ！
Don't you say! The dubbing is getting done next week.
What's wrong, Tarou-kun?
どうしたの？　太郎君
いや いいです
おなかいっぱいです
I'm fine, just full.
Coloring and dubbing should be done this week. It'll be fine.
Just realized.
（太郎）でした…
（丸川）えっ？
I hope it stays that way.
Oi-chan, Oi-chan! Were you watching?
おいちゃん おいちゃん
ちゃんと見れた？
Yeah! It was moving! Amazing!
見れた 見れた！
動いてたね　すごいよ！
But you've seen it so many times already...
もう何べんも見たでしょ？
But thousands, maybe millions of people are now watching with us on TV!
でも テレビは何十万
何百万人の人が
一緒に見てるんだよ　一緒に！
Right...
そう… だね
I guess if you look at it that way, it is amazing.
そう考えると すごいかな？
Later, guys.
お先です
See you!
（あおい）お疲れさまで～す
（本田）お疲れ～
See you.
Exodus! Keyframe Check Chart
Once this chart gets filled and episode 4 is done,
（あおい）
俺 この進行表が全部埋まって
４話が完成したら
I'll hit Pekka Donuts in Kichijoji and eat all they've got!
吉祥寺(きちじょうじ)のペッカドーナツ
一気食いするんだ
What's wrong, Tarou-san?
どうしたんですか？　タロさん
まだ帰らないんですか？
You're not going home yet?
いやっ まあ ちょっとね うん…
Got a few things I need to take care of!
Tarou.
（本田）太郎
（太郎）でひっ！
Finish updating the material for episode 3's rush check?
（本田）
３話のラッシュ
差し替え終わってるか？
Miyamori-san, could you take notes for me tomorrow?
宮森さん あした記録頼める？
Sure. It starts at noon, right?
（あおい）
はい　12時からですよね？
Yeah...
Good morning!
（興津(おきつ)）おはようございます
（一同）おはようございま～す
Good morning.
Good morning everyone.
はい おはよう
Exodus's episode 1, our first project as a main contractor in seven years, aired last night.
ゆうべ 我が社が
７年ぶりに元請けになる作品
「えくそだすっ！」の
第１話が放映されました
It's only 1-cour, but please keep up the good work for the remaining 12 episodes.
たった１クールですが
あと12本
気を抜かずに
頑張っていきましょう
A few messages from the production manager:
デスクから連絡で～す
Remember that today at 12:00,
we're doing the all-rush of episode 3.
本日12時から３話の
オールラッシュを行います
Episode 7 cutting is scheduled for 17:00 today.
17時から７話
カッティングの予定です
At 16:00 we're doing a 3D check of episode 6.
16時から６話の
３Ｄチェックをやります
Okitsu Yuka
General Affairs
Please remember to turn off the air
conditioning if you're the last one to leave.
総務からですが
最後に帰る人は 必ずエアコンを
消すようにしてください
Also, some items in the refrigerator are expired.
あと冷蔵庫に 賞味期限の
切れた物がいくつかあります
Toss them out before this weekend.
今週末までに片づけてください
That's all.
（興津）以上です
（一同）はい
Got it.
Then let's wo—
では本日も… じゃなかった
I mean, exodus into tomorrow!
明日に向かって えくそだ～すっ！
Yay...
Rush Room
Stop it there.
（円）
ラッシュ止めろ
Rewind and show me again.
戻して もっかい見せて
Wait, why is that still at storyboard?
（本田）
あれっ コンテ撮のまま？
Why isn't it colored yet?
なんで色ついてないの？
あっ！　そういや俺
Oh God, I just remembered that I haven't checked this part yet!
まだ このカット
チェックしてなかった～
So what's going on?
（円）
これさあ なんで？
Yes!
（太郎）
はい…
It wasn't a yes-no question.
（円）“はい”じゃないよね？
（太郎）はい！
Of course!
Do you realize what happens if we use the storyboard for the rush?
（円）
ラッシュがコンテのままって
どういうことか分かる？
We can't check the timing of the
movements or add sound effects!
動きのタイミングも分からないし
効果音もつけられないよね？
（太郎）
はい！
Of course!
Meaning we can't do the dubbing, meaning it won't be finished!
つまりダビングできない
（円）完成しないってことだよね？
（太郎）はい！
Of course!
Am I wrong?
俺の言うこと間違ってる？
Of course!
（太郎）はい！
（あおい･本田）えっ！
I-I mean, no, you're not wrong!
（太郎）
じゃじゃじゃ… じゃなくて
間違ってまへん！
T-Tell me you just forgot to splice in that cut.
まっ… まあまあまあ…
あれだよね？
ただの差し替えミスだよね？
絵の素材はあるんだもんね？
You do have all the frames, right?
I'm terribly sorry!
申し訳ありません！
実は原画は上がっておりません！
The keyframes aren't done yet!
And we don't have an ETA!
上がる予定もございません！
Did I not tell you over and over and over again?
何べんも 何べんも な～んべんも
俺言ったよな？
"The key animator's great,
but slow, so stay on top of it!"
あの人 絵はうまいけど
遅いから気をつけろって
はい！
Yes!
I guess I should have noticed earlier, but still...
そりゃあ俺も もっと早く
気付くべきだったけどさ
Yes—
はい… あっ！
I let my guard down because you kept saying it was gonna be fine!
お前が“大丈夫っす”っつうから
任せたんじゃねえか！
I really thought it was!
ダイジョブくありませんでした
Two days ago, he bailed and threw it back at us!
やっぱ無理って
おととい戻されました
Don't give me that!
Find another keyframe animator!
（円）
“ジョブく”じゃねえよ！
代わりの原画マン探せよ！
I tried asking everyone I knew,
いや 一応俺の持ってるカード
全部使ったんですけど
but they all said no.
ことごとく
ノーでございました
What do we do, director?
（円）どうしましょう 監督？
（木下）うん？
Do we keep it or cut it?
視聴継続か切りか
Episode 3 has the show's first climax.
Exodus!
最初に山場の第３話
更にそれの見せ場の超重要カット
And the key cuts we need are part of it.
We can't make it a 10-plus-seconds-long still frame.
それがただの止め絵で
十数秒なんてことになったら…
あっ あが…
Can't we handle this somehow in-house?
社内でなんとかできないですかね？
How about Hashimoto-san or Uchida-san?
橋本(はしもと)さんとか内田さんとか
う～ん まだ無理じゃね？
They can't handle it.
Then what about Sugie-san?
Sugie Shigeru
Keyframe Animator
（本田）
杉江(すぎえ)さんは？
You think asking him to draw moe anime is a good idea? No way.
（円）
萌(も)えアニメなんて―
描けるわけねえじゃん
ありえねえって あの人　無理！
What about Yasuhara-san?
（本田）
安原(やすはら)さんとか？
You can't entrust this to a newbie!
（円）
新人原画には まだ無理だろ
勝負カットだぞ
It's really important!
Then I'm out of ideas!
万策尽きた～！
Couldn't we ask Segawa-san?
瀬川さんに頼めないかな？
Episode 4's animation director?
（あおい）ハッ！
（本田）４話の作監の？
Great idea!
（円）なるほど！
（あおい）はあっ！
P-P-Please wait!
まままま… 待って！
It's a real doozy.
When do you need the keyframes by?
重っ！　原画アップいつまで？
The morning after tomorrow, at the latest.
あさって午前中… みたいな
That's impossible!
それは無理！
お願いします！
瀬川さんにしか頼めないんです！
Please, I beg you! You're our last hope!
Please!
しゃあっす！
We'll have someone handle cleanup. Rough keyframes will do.
二原も立てます
ラフ原でかまいませんから
I'm not doing that. If I do it, I have to do it right.
それはやだ
やるなら ちゃんとやりたいし
But if I'm doing this,
what will happen to episode 4?
もし私がこれをやったら
４話はどうするの？
Isn't the AD up deadline tomorrow?
あした作監アップなんでしょ？
それはいったん 止めていただいて
If you could maybe put that aside for now...
Also, isn't the AD for episode 3 Endou-kun?
それと３話の作監 遠藤(えんどう)君でしょ？
遠藤君と演出の円さんは
なんて言ってるの？
What did Endou-kun and episode director Madoka-san say about this?
Endou Ryousuke
Animation Director
Segawa-san, huh?
（遠藤）
瀬川さんか～
おっ 遠藤って瀬川さん苦手？
You two don't get along?
That's not the problem.
I just wish they'd told me beforehand.
いや 苦手ってことはないですけど
前もって言ってほしかったな
You're rivals after all.
I guess you don't want to owe her one.
ライバルだもんな
借りは作りたくないと
It's got nothing to do with that!
貸しとか借りとかないですから！
ちょっと絵柄が合わないだけですよ
Our styles are just a bit different.
But your hands are full doing animation retakes, right?
んなこと言ったって 実際問題
お前 作画リテーク対応で
作監 手いっぱいだろ？
You're the one asking for them, Madoka-san!
それは円さんが
いっぱい出すからじゃないですか
Hey, it's not me. It's the director.
俺じゃないよ　監督だよ
（携帯電話の着信音）
Ah, Honda.
ああ 本田？
お疲れさまです
How's it going?
Huh? Really?
えっ ホント？
He doesn't seem happy with
Segawa-san doing it though—
ああ～ でも瀬川さんじゃ
どうも不満っぽい…
Hey, hold on!
ちょちょ… 待って！
I never said I wasn't happy about it!
不満なんて
全然言ってませんから！
On the contrary, I'd be honored if she did it!
むしろ やっていただけるなら
むっちゃ光栄です
He said he'd really appreciate it.
“頼めるなら ぜひお願いしたい”
って言ってました
（瀬川）ホントかな？
（太郎）しゃあっす！
Really?
Please!
Is episode 4 really gonna be okay?
４話 ホントに大丈夫？
I hope so...
多分… じゃなくて
はい 大丈夫です！
I mean, yes, it will!
I'll make it happen! Leave it to me!
なんとかしたい　なんとかします！
（瀬川）う～ん…
（太郎）しゃあっす！
Please!
Takanashi-kun, was it?
（瀬川）高梨(たかなし)君だっけ？
（太郎）しゃあっす！
Please.
Can Miyamori-san come pick it up instead of you?
（瀬川）
回収はきみじゃなくて
宮森さんにお願いできるかな？
You're pretty annoying.
（瀬川）ちょっとそれイラっとする
（太郎）えっ？
Please...
しゃあっす…
Segawa-san's style doesn't mesh with mine.
俺 瀬川さんと
あんま合わないんですよ
The way she draws is so logical and calculated.
彼女って
理詰めで描くじゃないっすか
It's not very dynamic.
けれんみに欠けるっていうか
Doesn't that make you a runaway train, always just following your gut?
そういうお前は
感覚最優先の暴走列車じゃね？
That's what the cut asks for!
（遠藤）
だって そういうカットですよね？
I get it, I get it.
Just get the retakes fixed, all right?
分かったから　とにかく
リテーク修正しっかり頼むぞ
Segawa-san's really amazing...
いや～ 瀬川さん
マジすげえ
I heard she had a fight with director Tomioka and won.
あの人 トミオカ監督とケンカして
勝ったらしいからね～
That's not it. Those things would fill up a light box!
じゃなくて ライトボックスに
乗っかりますよね？
Ah, that.
It's not that easy.
大変なんですよ！
Huh?
It really isn't.
ホントもう 大変なんですから！
おっ お疲れ みゃーもり
Welcome back, Meowmori.
Hello.
お疲れさまで～す
Oh right, Shinkawa-san from coloring wanted to have a word with you.
あっ そうだ 仕上げの新川さん
顔出せって言ってたよ
Got it.
はい 分かりました
Goodbye.
（杉江）
お先～
See you later!
（矢野･あおい）
お疲れさまで～す
You're putting episode 4 on hold?
４話 止めたんだって？
Yes.
（あおい）
はい
はあ～ そこは
断るところだったと思うけどね
You should've just refused.
PA's can't just agree to everything.
はいはい言うだけが進行じゃないよ
I'm sorry.
（あおい）
すみません
We can't do anything about keyframe animation being delayed.
（新川）
作画に時間取られるのは
ある程度しょうがない
But not having animation director checks for two days
でも ２日
作監作業が止まると
うちらは実質 それ以上
作業時間がなくなることになるよね
means that we'll have even less time on our hands!
We'll be the ones getting the short end of the stick.
尻ぬぐいをするのは
こっちなんだよ
Sorry...
はい…
I'd say you should also talk with Sakura-san at filming
撮影の佐倉さんにも
ちゃんと説明したほうが
いいと思うよ
about the schedule.
スケジュールのこと
I don't mind.
いいよ 別に
撮影は待つのも仕事だからね
Waiting is part of our job as well.
I'm sorry.
すみません
But in a TV series, you know,
（佐倉）
テレビシリーズってのはさ
１話コケたら その後 全部
once one episode falls behind,
they all begin to fall like dominoes.
バタバタって
ドミノ倒しになるんだよ
Keep that in mind.
それだけ覚えててくれれば
I will!
（あおい）
あっ はい！
Great, this looks fantastic!
（丸川）
イェイ イェイ イェイイェイ♪
…と
おお うまそうだ ハハッ
Good brown sugar does wonders!
いい黒糖使うと違うな～
（ドアが開く音）
（興津）失礼します
Excuse me.
Ah, Okitsu-san!
ああ興津さん あしたはモツね
モツ煮込み とろっとろだよ
Tomorrow we're having motsu! Stewed motsu!
I'm making it extra thick!
President, the tenants from the floor below are complaining about the smell.
社長 下のフロアから
においの苦情が来ています
Ah, sorry.
ああ… ごめん
Also, there was an email from Varner Siblings Studios.
それから ヴァーナ兄弟社の
プロデューサーから
メール来てました
He said Exodus is great.
“「えくそだすっ！」面白い”って
ホ… ホント？
Really?
Home sweet home...
（あおい）
ただいま～
は～！　ドーナツ食べたい！
I want donuts!
Donuts! Donuts! I wanna go nuts!
ドーナツ ドーナツ
ど～んといきたいよ～！
To Aoi
You'll get fat!
（あおい）
デブるよ？
One or two's no big deal!
Sweets help when you're tired or feel down!
いいじゃん
疲れた時 ヘコんだ時には
甘い物だよ
What? It's your fault you're down!
はあ？　自業自得！
You knew it'd delay AD work!
Why didn't you refuse?
４話の作監作業が
ストップしちゃうのに
なんで断らないのさ！
How could I refuse the director and the PM?
監督とデスクに言われちゃ
断れないよ～
Make mincemeat of him.
ミンチにしちゃえ！
えっ？
Huh?
Tarou.
太郎
Mince and pound and grind him down!
こねて こねて
こねくりまくって
Into hamburger steak?
ハンバーグ？
Nope, trash him!
捨てる！
So mean!
ひどい～！
At 16:00 today, dubbing for
episode 3 begins at R&B Studio.
本日16時よりＲ＆Ｂスタジオで
３話のダビングです！
How are Segawa-san's keyframes for episode 3?
３話の瀬川さんの原画は？
She said she'll be done around 13:00.
13時ごろになるそうです
The intense summer heat... even in shade... be careful...
（ラジオ:男）
残暑の暑さも陰りが見え…
I'm cutting it close...
綱渡りか…
This is Miyamori!
はい 宮森です！
Ah, right. I got them.
ああ うん 届いてるよ
Thanks!
ありがとう
うん ごめん　おいしかった
Sorry, sorry. They were great.
:
10/8 Wed 1 01 PM
Production 9
:
How's Segawa-san going?
瀬川さん どう？
She'll be done any moment now.
（あおい）
もう上がると思います
You need to be more aggressive!
Don't be so soft!
直撃してせっつけよ
ツメが甘いんだよな
（あおい）
ミンチ…
Mincemeat.
Two-and-a-half hours until the dubbing.
ダビングまで あと２時間半
Maybe I should go to Segawa-san's place and wait there?
瀬川さんとこ行って
直接待機したほうが…
Right!
よし… うわ～っ！　あっ！
（携帯電話のバイブ音）
Musani, Miyamori speaking!
はい ムサニの宮森です！
Right! Got it!
はい 分かりました！
すぐに伺います！
I'll be there right away!
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました！
失礼します！
Excuse me!
Is it done?
（矢野）上がった？
（あおい）上がりました！
It's done!
よしっ！
演出と撮影のスタンバイ！
Great!
Director and filming to standby!
イェッサー！
Yes sir!
Sorry for taking so long...
遅れちゃってごめん
ダビング大丈夫？
Will you be in time for the dubbing?
We'll make it somehow!
バリバリ大丈夫です！
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
（円）
ここでぶつかる音と…
The sound of them crashing goes here.
Check.
チェック
Episode
Director
Dubbing's good to go.
これでダビングいける！
Episode
Director
（佐倉）
えっ ダビングまであと１時間？
An hour until the dubbing?
Get real! I can get this done in 20 minutes!
何言ってんの？
20分あれば余裕だよ
（木下）う～ん…
（矢野）お疲れさまで～す
I'm off to the dubbing!
（円）ダビング行ってきま～す
（木下）はい 行ってらっしゃ～い
Take care!
Oh, the Chuo line's stopped
because of an accident again.
（落合）
あれ？
また中央線 人身で止まってる
マジで？　太郎は… そっか
動仕まき出たばっかか
For real?
Tarou—
Oh right, he just left.
Ah, Miyamori-san!
Take Madoka-san to the dubbing, please!
ああ 宮森さん
円さんをダビングに連れてって
He just left, so you can still catch him!
今出たところだから捕まえて！
あっ はい！
Right!
Miyamori, is this your first time going to a dubbing?
宮森ってダビング初めてだっけ？
見学していけばいいのに
Why not stay and check it out?
したいんですけど
４話が控えてるんで
I'd love to, but I can't delay episode 4 any further.
That's true.
それもそっか
Good afternoon.
（円）
お疲れさまです
（一同）
お疲れさまで～す
Good afternoon.
Segawa-san made it on time?
（木下）瀬川さん 間に合ったんだ
（円）やっぱ すげえっす
She really is amazing...
Ah, it's not colored yet?
Exodus
（稲浪(いななみ)）ああ 色つきじゃないんだ
（円）勘弁してくださいよ
Give us a break.
One plain, one soy flour,
and one chocolate, split into two bags.
Pekka Donuts
プレーンときな粉と
チョコレートの３つを
二袋に分けて…
Actually, one bag will be fine.
ああ… いや やっぱし
１つの袋でいいです
It's Miyamori Aoi from Musashino Animation!
武蔵野アニメーションの
宮森あおいです
Hello, this is Musashino Animation!
Ah, Kisa-san!
What? You won't be done today?
Next time on Shirobako: "Alpine's Here!"
Alpine's Here!
（あおい）
はい 武蔵野アニメーションです
あっ 木佐さん
えっ やっぱり今日上がらない？
次回「SHIROBAKO(シロバコ)」